Thomas F. Bayard Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Thomas F. Bayard Papers 1780-1899 1860-1889
MSS12088
Bayard, Thomas F. (Thomas Francis), 1828-1898
60,000 items
220 containers plus 18 oversize
49.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Senator, secretary of state, and ambassador. Correspondence, letterbooks, scrapbooks, and miscellany relating to Bayard's career after the Civil War as a politician and legislator and as a cabinet official and diplomat during the presidential administrations of Grover Cleveland.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Adee, Alvey A. (Alvey Augustus), 1842-1924--Correspondence.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916--Correspondence.; Baden-Powell, George, 1847-1898--Correspondence.; Baird family--Correspondence.; Bayard family--Correspondence.; Bayard, James A. (James Asheton), 1799-1880--Correspondence.; Bayard, Thomas F. (Thomas Francis), 1828-1898.; Belmont, August, Sr., 1813-1890--Correspondence.; Belmont, Perry, 1850-1947--Correspondence.; Breckinridge, William Campbell Preston, 1837-1904--Correspondence.; Bryan, Henry Lewis, 1853-1934--Correspondence.; Butler, M. C. (Matthew Calbraith), 1836-1909--Correspondence.; Carroll, John Lee, 1830-1911--Correspondence.; Casserly, Eugene, 1820-1883--Correspondence.; Chamberlain, Joseph, 1836-1914--Correspondence.; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908--Correspondence.; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908.; Cox, Samuel Sullivan, 1824-1889--Correspondence.; Denby, Charles, 1830-1904--Correspondence.; Dickinson, Donald McDonald, 1846-1917--Correspondence.; Du Pont, Henry, 1812-1889--Correspondence.; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926--Correspondence.; Endicott, William Crowninshield, 1826-1900--Correspondence.; Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901--Correspondence.; Fairchild, Charles S. (Charles Stebbins), 1842-1924--Correspondence.; Fish, Hamilton, 1808-1893--Correspondence.; Ford, Worthington Chauncey, 1858-1941--Correspondence.; Gallaudet, Edward Miner, 1837-1917--Correspondence.; Garland, A. H. (Augustus Hill), 1832-1899--Correspondence.; Gordon, John Brown, 1832-1904--Correspondence.; Gresham, Walter Quintin, 1832-1895--Correspondence.; Hampton, Wade, 1818-1902--Correspondence.; Hayes, Rutherford B., 1822-1893.; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904--Correspondence.; Hurlbert, William Henry, 1827-1895--Correspondence.; Lamar, L. Q. C. (Lucius Quintus Cincinnatus), 1825-1893--Correspondence.; Lamont, Daniel Scott, 1851-1905--Correspondence.; Lincoln, Robert Todd, 1843-1926--Correspondence.; Manning, Daniel, 1831-1887--Correspondence.; Manning, Thomas C. (Thomas Courtland), 1831-1887--Correspondence.; Marble, Manton, 1834-1917--Correspondence.; McLane, Robert M. (Robert Milligan), 1815-1898--Correspondence.; Moore, John Bassett, 1860-1947--Correspondence.; Morrill, Justin S. (Justin Smith), 1810-1898--Correspondence.; Olney, Richard, 1835-1917--Correspondence.; Page, Walter Hines, 1855-1918--Correspondence.; Peabody, George Foster, 1852-1938--Correspondence.; Pendleton, George H. (George Hunt), 1825-1889--Correspondence.; Phelps, Edward John, 1822-1900--Correspondence.; Playfair, Lyon Playfair, Baron, 1818-1898--Correspondence.; Porter, Fitz-John, 1822-1901--Correspondence.; Porter, Fitz-John, 1822-1901.; Sackville, Lionel Sackville Sackville-West, Baron, 1827-1908--Correspondence.; Sackville, Lionel Sackville Sackville-West, Baron, 1827-1908.; Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906--Correspondence.; Sherman, John, 1823-1900--Correspondence.; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891--Correspondence.; Straus, Oscar S. (Oscar Solomon), 1850-1926--Correspondence.; Tilden, Samuel J. (Samuel Jones), 1814-1886.; Vilas, William F. (William Freeman), 1840-1908--Correspondence.; Wells, David A. (David Ames), 1828-1898--Correspondence.; Wharton, Francis, 1820-1889--Correspondence.; White, Henry, 1850-1927--Correspondence.; White, Horace, 1834-1916--Correspondence.; Whitney, William C. (William Collins), 1841-1904--Correspondence.; Wister, Owen, 1860-1938--Correspondence.
Organizations
United States. Congress. Senate.; United States. Department of State.
Subjects
Diplomatic and consular service, American--Great Britain.; Fishery law and legislation.; Presidents--United States--Election.; Real estate investment.; Sealing--Law and legislation.; Silver question.; Tariff--United States.; Transit, International.
Places
China--Foreign relations--Japan.; Delaware--Politics and government--1865-1950.; Germany--Foreign relations--United States.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--United States.; Hawaii--Annexation to the United States.; Japan--Foreign relations--China.; Korea--History--1864-1910.; Panama Canal (Panama)--History.; Samoan Islands--History.; United States--Economic policy--To 1933.; United States--Foreign relations--1865-1898.; United States--Foreign relations--Germany.; United States--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; United States--Politics and government--1865-1900.; Venezuela--Boundaries.
Occupations
Ambassadors.; Cabinet officers.; Lawyers.; Senators, U.S. Congress--Delaware.; Statesmen.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Thomas F. Bayard, senator, secretary of state, and diplomat, were given to the Library of Congress from 1933 to 1963, principally by Bayard's daughter, Florence Bayard Hilles, via Charles Callan Tansill. Small additions were made by Helen Tansill, D. H. Mugridge, and John de Porry.
Additional Guides
The collection was described in the Report of the Librarian of Congress, 1933, p. 28; 1934, p. 36.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Thomas F. Bayard are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1828, Oct. 29 Born, Wilmington, Del.
1851 Admitted to the Delaware bar
1853 1854 United States district attorney for Delaware
1854 1857 Practiced law, Philadelphia, Pa.
1856 Married Louise Lee (died 1886)
1856 1869 Practiced law, Wilmington, Del.
1869 1885 United States senator
1872 Delegate to the Democratic Party national convention, Baltimore, Md.
1876 Candidate for Democratic Party presidential nomination
1877 Appointed a member of the Electoral Commission by act of Congress to decide the contests in various states in the presidential election of 1876
1880 Candidate for Democratic Party presidential nomination
1881 Elected president pro tempore of the Senate
1884 Candidate for Democratic Party presidential nomination
1885 1889 Secretary of state
1889 Married Mary W. Clymer
1893 1897 Ambassador to Great Britain
1898, Sept. 28 Died, Dedham, Mass.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Thomas Francis Bayard (1828-1898) consist of correspondence, letterbooks, financial records, legal papers, notes, reports, memoranda, photographs, speeches, printed matter, scrapbooks, and related material. The collection spans the years 1780-1899, with the bulk of the material dated 1860-1898.
The papers relate generally to Bayard's career as a senator, 1869-1885, secretary of state during President Grover Cleveland's first administration, 1885-1889, and as ambassador to Great Britain, 1893-1897, during Cleveland's second administration. The collection contains files pertaining to real estate and financial matters, national politics, the Fitz-John Porter case, Samoa, fisheries and sealing questions, the Venezuelan boundary dispute, Anglo-American and German-American relations, presidential campaigns, the silver question, the Tilden-Hayes election, tariff problems, Sir Lionel S. Sackville-West, the conflict between China and Japan over the vassalage of Korea, American annexation of Hawaii, and the Isthmian transit and canal problem.
Correspondents in addition to members of the Bayard family include Alvey Augustus Adee, James Burrill Angell, George Baden-Powell, James A. Bayard, August Belmont, Perry Belmont, William Campbell Preston Breckinridge, Henry L. Bryan, M. C. Butler, John Lee Carroll, Eugene Casserly, Joseph Chamberlain, Grover Cleveland, Samuel S. Cox, Charles Denby, Donald M. Dickinson, Henry A. DuPont, Charles W. Eliot, William C. Endicott, William M. Evarts, Charles S. Fairchild, Hamilton Fish (1808-1893), Worthington C. Ford, Edward M. Gallaudet, Augustus H. Garland, John Brown Gordon, Walter Q. Gresham, Wade Hampton, George F. Hoar, William Henry Hurlbert, Lucius Q. C. Lamar, Daniel S. Lamont, Robert Todd Lincoln, Daniel Manning, Thomas C. Manning, Manton Marble, Robert M. McLane, John Bassett Moore, Justin S. Morrill, Richard Olney, Walter Hines Page, George Foster Peabody, George H. Pendleton, Edward John Phelps, Lord Lyon Playfair, Fitz-John Porter, Sir Lionel S. Sackville-West, Carl Schurz, John Sherman, William T. Sherman, Oscar S. Straus, William F. Vilas, David Ames Wells, Francis Wharton, Henry White, Horace White, William C. Whitney, and Owen Wister.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in five series:
General Correspondence, 1780-1899
Letterbooks, 1885-1898
Miscellany, 1824-1898
Scrapbooks, 1847-1892
Oversize, 1879-1892
Container List
- General Correspondence, 1780-1899 (Box 1-193)
  - Bound, 1796-1899 (Box 1-177)
    Bound volumes of letters received with occasional drafts of letters sent and telegrams, memoranda, and related reports, speeches, financial records, papers, printed matter, and newspaper clippings.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1796, July 15-1859, June 23 (Box 1)
    - 1859, Feb. 19-1860, July 10 (Box 2)
    - 1860, Feb. 19-July 10 (Box 3)
    - 1860, July 11-1861, Jan. 17 (Box 4)
    - 1861, Jan. 18-June 23 (Box 5)
    - 1861, June 24-1862, Jan. 23 (Box 6)
    - 1862, Jan. 26-1863, Feb.1 (Box 7)
    - 1863, Feb. 3-1864, Jan. 2 (Box 8)
    - 1864, Jan. 6-July, 20 (Box 9)
    - 1864, July 23-1865, Feb. 13 (Box 10)
    - 1865, Feb. 14-1867, Oct. 31 (Box 11)
    - 1867, Nov. 1-1868, Feb. 6 (Box 12)
    - 1868 (Box 13)
      - Feb.7-Apr. 13
      - Apr. 14-July 20 (Box 14)
      - July 22-Nov. 18 (Box 15)
    - 1868, July 19-1869, Jan. 20 (Box 16)
    - 1869 (Box 17)
      - Jan. 26-Apr. 19
      - Apr. 20-Oct. 11 (Box 18)
    - 1869, Oct. 12-1870, Feb. 4 (Box 19)
    - 1870, Feb. 7-June 29 (Box 20)
    - 1870, June 30-1871, Apr. 17 (Box 21)
    - 1871, Apr. 18-1872, Jan. 10 (Box 22)
    - 1872 (Box 23)
      - Jan. 11-Mar. 28
      - Mar. 29-Oct. 8 (Box 24)
    - 1872, Oct. 11-1873, July 11 (Box 25)
    - 1873, July 12-June 11 (Box 26)
    - 1874, June 12-1875, Jan. 11 (Box 27)
    - 1875 (Box 28)
      - Jan. 12-Feb. 12
      - Feb. 13-Apr. 20 (Box 29)
      - Apr. 21-Dec. 18 (Box 30)
    - 1875, Dec. 25-1876, Apr. 3 (Box 31)
    - 1876, Apr. 7-Oct. 8 (Box 32)
    - 1876, Oct. 27-1877, Jan. 30 (Box 33)
    - 1877 (Box 34)
      - Jan. 31-Feb. 15
      - Feb. 16-May 4 (Box 35)
      - May 6-Aug. 14 (Box 36)
      - Aug. 15-Nov. 19 (Box 37)
      - Nov. 20-Dec. 31 (Box 38)
    - 1878 (Box 39)
      - Jan. 1- Feb. 9
      - Feb. 11- Apr. 4 (Box 40)
      - Apr. 5-May 22 (Box 41)
      - May 23- July 29 (Box 42)
      - July 30- Nov. 22 (Box 43)
    - 1878, Nov. 23-1879, Jan. 13 (Box 44)
    - 1879 (Box 45)
      - Jan. 14-Feb. 13
      - Feb. 14-Mar. 10 (Box 46)
      - Mar. 11-Apr. 1 (Box 47)
      - Apr. 2-May 14 (Box 48)
      - May 15-July 7 (Box 49)
      - July 8-Nov. 28 (Box 50)
      - Nov. 29-Dec. 31 (Box 51)
    - 1879, no month or day-1880, Feb. 3 (Box 52)
    - 1880 (Box 53)
      - Feb. 4-Mar. 14
      - Mar. 15-May 1 (Box 54)
      - May 5-June 15 (Box 55)
      - June 16-Aug. 19 (Box 56)
      - Aug. 20-Oct. 22 (Box 57)
    - 1880, Oct. 23-1881, Jan. 21 (Box 58)
    - 1881, Jan. 23-May 30 (Box 59)
    - 1881, June 3-1882, Jan. 20 (Box 60)
    - 1882, Jan. 24-Aug. 6 (Box 61)
    - 1882, Aug. 7-1883, Jan. 22 (Box 62)
    - 1883, Jan. 24-June 21 (Box 63)
    - 1883, June 26-1884, Jan. 11 (Box 64)
    - 1884 (Box 65)
      - Jan. 14-June 20
      - June 21-Nov. 12 (Box 66)
      - Nov. 13-Dec. 9 (Box 67)
    - 1884, Dec. 11-1885, Jan. 7 (Box 68)
    - 1885 (Box 69)
      - Jan. 8-5
      - Feb. 6-26 (Box 70)
      - Feb. 27-Mar. 11 (Box 71)
      - Mar. 12-28 (Box 72)
      - Mar. 29-Apr. 18 (Box 73)
      - Apr. 19-May 7 (Box 74)
      - May 8-28 (Box 75)
      - May 29-June 19 (Box 76)
      - June 20-July 7 (Box 77)
      - July 8-Aug. 3 (Box 78)
      - Aug. 4-31 (Box 79)
      - Sept. 1-30 (Box 80)
      - Oct. 1-23 (Box 81)
      - Oct. 24-Nov. 27 (Box 82)
      - Nov. 28-Dec. 25 (Box 83)
    - 1885, Dec. 26-1886, Jan. 7 (Box 84)
    - 1886 (Box 85)
      - Jan. 8- Feb. 25
      - Feb. 26-Mar. 30 (Box 86)
      - Mar. 31-May 5 (Box 87)
      - May 6-25 (Box 88)
      - May 26-June 15 (Box 89)
      - June 16-July 5 (Box 90)
      - July 6-16 (Box 91)
      - July 17-Aug. 2 (Box 92)
      - Aug. 3-17 (Box 93)
      - Aug. 17-Sept. 3 (Box 94)
      - Sept. 4- 24 (Box 95)
      - Sept. 25-Oct. 16 (Box 96)
      - Oct. 17-Nov. 11 (Box 97)
      - Nov. 12-29 (Box 98)
      - Nov. 30-Dec. 20 (Box 99)
      - Dec. 21-31 (Box 100)
    - 1887 (Box 101)
      - Jan. 1-21
      - Jan. 22-Feb. 8 (Box 102)
      - Feb. 9-22 (Box 103)
      - Feb. 23-Mar. 11 (Box 104)
      - Mar. 12-31 (Box 105)
      - Apr. 1-24 (Box 106)
      - Apr. 25-May 13 (Box 107)
      - May 14-June 1 (Box 108)
      - June 2-22 (Box 109)
      - June 23-July 22 (Box 110)
      - July 23-Aug. 29 (Box 111)
      - Aug. 29-Sept. 25 (Box 112)
      - Sept. 26-Oct. 14 (Box 113)
      - Oct. 15- 29 (Box 114)
      - Oct. 30-Nov. 15 (Box 115)
      - Nov. 16-Dec. 7 (Box 116)
      - Dec. 8-31 (Box 117)
    - 1887, no month or day-1888, Jan. 3 (Box 118)
    - 1888 (Box 119)
      - Jan. 4-21
      - Jan. 22-Feb. 10 (Box 120)
      - Feb. 11-23 (Box 121)
      - Feb. 29-Mar. 17 (Box 122)
      - Mar. 19-Apr. 5 (Box 123)
      - Apr. 6-May 1 (Box 124)
      - May 2-26 (Box 125)
      - May 26-June 25 (Box 126)
      - June 26-July 30 (Box 127)
      - July 31-Aug. 22 (Box 128)
      - Aug. 23-Sept. 12 (Box 129)
      - Sept. 13-25 (Box 130)
      - Oct. 26-Nov. 14 (Box 131)
      - Nov. 15-Dec. 15 (Box 132)
      - Dec. 16-31 (Box 133)
    - 1888, undated-1889, Jan. 4 (Box 134)
    - 1889 (Box 135)
      - Jan. 5-Feb. 1
      - Feb. 2-27 (Box 136)
      - Feb. 28-Sept. 22 (Box 137)
    - 1889, Sept. 23-1890, Jan. 3 (Box 138)
    - 1890 (Box 139)
      - Jan. 4-Apr. 3
      - Apr. 4-Oct. 30 (Box 140)
    - 1890, Nov. 1-1891, May 13 (Box 141)
    - 1891, May 14-Nov. 24 (Box 142)
    - 1891, Nov. 27-1892, Apr. 10 (Box 143)
    - 1892, Apr. 13-Nov. 10 (Box 144)
    - 1892, Nov. 11-1893, Feb. 27 (Box 145)
    - 1893 (Box 146)
      - Feb. 28-Mar. 30
      - Mar. 31 (Box 147)
      - Apr. 1-13 (Box 148)
      - Apr. 14-May 29 (Box 149)
      - May 30-July 10 (Box 150)
      - July 11-Sept. 26 (Box 151)
      - Sept. 30-Dec. 12 (Box 152)
    - 1893, Dec. 13-1894, Feb. 12 (Box 153)
    - 1894 (Box 154)
      - Feb. 13-Apr. 7
      - Apr. 8-July 11 (Box 155)
      - July 13-Nov. 2 (Box 156)
      - Nov. 3-Dec. 31 (Box 157)
    - 1895 (Box 158)
      - Jan. 1-Mar. 13
      - Mar. 14-May 25 (Box 159)
      - May 28-Aug. 11 (Box 160)
      - Aug. 12-Nov. 27 (Box 161)
      - Nov. 30-Dec. 31 (Box 162)
    - 1896 (Box 163)
      - Jan. 1-31
      - Feb. 1-Mar. 6 (Box 164)
      - Mar. 9-May 12 (Box 165)
      - May 13-Aug. 9 (Box 166)
      - Aug. 10-Oct. 13 (Box 167)
      - Oct. 14-Nov. 4 (Box 168)
      - Nov. 5-Dec. 8 (Box 169)
    - 1896, Dec. 9-1897, Jan. 14 (Box 170)
    - 1897 (Box 171)
      - Jan. 15-Mar. 1
      - Mar. 2-May 4 (Box 172)
      - May 5-June 27 (Box 173)
      - June 28-Aug. 17 (Box 174)
    - 1897, Aug. 19-1898, May 3 (Box 175)
    - 1898, May 14-1899, Feb. 7 (Box 176)
    - Undated
      - “B-W” miscellaneous
      - Unidentified (Box 177)
  - Unbound, 1780-1898 (Box 178-193)
    Letters and telegrams received and drafts of correspondence sent.
    - 1780, 1812-1871, (21 folders) (Box 178)
    - 1872, Jan.-1876, Apr., (16 folders) (Box 179)
    - 1876, May-1878, Apr., (15 folders) (Box 180)
    - 1878, May-1879, June, (13 folders) (Box 181)
    - 1879, July-1880, June, (13 folders) (Box 182)
    - 1880, July-1884, June, (9 folders) (Box 183)
    - 1884, July-1885, Mar., (14 folders) (Box 184)
    - 1885, Apr.-Nov., (14 folders) (Box 185)
    - 1885, Dec.-1886, Dec., (16 folders) (Box 186)
    - 1887, Jan.-July, (16 folders) (Box 187)
    - 1887, Aug.-Dec., (8 folders) (Box 188)
    - 1888, (14 folders) (Box 189)
    - 1889, (14 folders) (Box 190)
    - 1890-1893, (13 folders) (Box 191)
    - 1894, Jan.-1897, June, (17 folders) (Box 192)
    - 1897, July-1898, Dec., undated, (12 folders) (Box 193)
- Letterbooks, 1885-1898 (Box 194-209)
  Letterpress and carbon copies of outgoing correspondence in three groupings from Bayard's career as secretary of state and ambassador to Great Britain. There is some overlapping between series.
  Arranged chronologically by earliest date of each volume.
  - Series I (Box 194)
    - 1885, Mar. 20-Nov. 20
    - 1885, Nov. 22-1886, June 22 (Box 195)
    - 1885, June 22-1886, Dec. 13 (Box 196)
    - 1886, Dec. 13-1887, Apr. 26 (Box 197)
    - 1887, Apr. 26-Aug. 29 (Box 198)
    - 1887, Aug. 30-1888, Jan. 11 (Box 199)
    - 1888 (Box 200)
      - Jan. 13-May 26
      - May 26- Sept. 26 (Box 201)
      - Sept. 26-Dec. 10 (Box 202)
    - 1888, Dec. 10-1889, Mar. 1 (Box 203)
  - Series II (Box 204)
    - 1893, July 12-1894, July 20
    - 1894, July 26-1895, June 8 (Box 205)
    - 1895, June 8-1896, Feb. 24 (Box 206)
    - 1896, Feb. 24-Dec. 4 (Box 207)
    - 1896, Dec. 5-1897, May 3 (Box 208)
  - Series III (Box 209)
    - 1890-1898
- Miscellany, 1824-1898 (Box 210-218)
  Announcements, calling cards, greeting cards, certificates, financial records, genealogical material, legal papers, maps, notes, drafts, reports, memoranda, transcripts, photographs, speeches, printed matter, and various topical files.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - Announcements, calling cards, and greeting cards, undated, (2 folders) (Box 210)
  - Bills and receipts, 1868-1897, (9 folders)
  - Certificates, 1880-1890
  - Financial records, 1868-1897, (2 folders)
  - Genealogy, 1879-1880
  - General, 1866, 1895-1897
  - Johnson Steel Co. of Lorain, Ohio, 1894-1898, (4 folders) (Box 211)
  - Legal papers, 1824-1898, (6 folders)
  - Maps, undated See Oversize (Box 212)
  - Notes, drafts, reports, memoranda, transcripts, and miscellaneous material, undated, (8 folders); (4 folders) (Box 213)
  - Photographs, undated, (2 folders)
  - Printed matter, circa 1865-1898, (3 folders); (5 folders); (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 214, Box 215, Box 216, Box 217)
  - Samoan Conference, 1887
  - Sermon by Archdeacon Sinclair concerning Bayard, 1897
  - Silver Mission, correspondence with Manton Marble and reports, 1885-1886, (2 folders)
  - Speeches, 1870-1897, (13 folders) (Box 218)
- Scrapbooks, 1847-1892 (Box 219-220)
  Bound volumes of newspaper clippings and printed matter. There is considerable overlapping between volumes.
  Arranged chronologically by earliest year of each volume.
  - 1847-1861 (Box 219)
  - 1870-1879
  - 1876-1879, (2 vols.) (Box 220)
  - 1879, silver question See Oversize
  - 1883 See Oversize
  - 1884, presidential campaign See Oversize
  - 1885 See Oversize
  - 1887-1888 See Oversize
    - "The Irish World"
    - Miscellany
  - 1887-1889 See Oversize
    - Samoa
    - Seal fisheries
  - 1888 See Oversize
    - Miscellany
    - Presidential election campaign
  - 1888-1889 See Oversize
    - Canadian fisheries, (2 vols.)
    - Miscellany
  - 1888-1892 See Oversize, (2 vols.)
  - 1889 See Oversize
  - 1889-1890 See Oversize
  - 1892
- Oversize, 1879-1892 (Box OV 1-OV 18)
  Maps and scrapbooks arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Maps, undated (Container 212)
  - Scrapbooks (Container 220) (Box OV 2)
    - 1879, silver question
    - 1883 (Box OV 3)
    - 1884, presidential campaign (Box OV 4)
    - 1885 (Box OV 5)
    - 1887-1888 (Box OV 6)
      - "The Irish World"
      - Miscellany (Box OV 7)
    - 1887-1889 (Box OV 8)
      - Samoa
      - Seal fisheries (Box OV 9)
    - 1888 (Box OV 10)
      - Miscellany
      - Presidential election campaign (Box OV 11)
    - 1888-1889 (Box OV 12)
      - Canadian fisheries, (1 vol.) (Box OV 13)
      - Miscellany (Box OV 14)
    - 1888-1892, (1 vol.) (Box OV 15, Box OV 16)
    - 1889 (Box OV 17)
    - 1889-1890 (Box OV 18)